A Finding Aid to the Billy Al Bengston Papers, circa 1940s-1989 (bulk 1960-1988), in the Archives of American Art AAA.bengbill
Archives of American Art
Billy Al Bengston papers
bulk 1960-1988
circa 1940s-1989
AAA.bengbill
Archives of American Art
10.2 Linear feet
The papers of southern California Pop artist Billy Al Bengston measure 10.2 linear feet and date from circa 1940s to 1989, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1960 to 1988. The collection documents the life and work of the artist through biographical materials, correspondence, personal business records, gallery and museum files, teaching files, project and commission files, scattered artwork, printed materials, and photographs.
Bengston, Billy Al
Provenance
The collection was donated to the Archives of American Art by Billy Al Bengston in 1990.
Related Material
Found in the Archives of American Art are oral history interviews with Bengston conducted by Susan Larsen, September 9, 1980, and Susan Ford Morgan, August 2-October 7, 2002. Also found are portraits of Bengston in the Photographs of artists taken by Mimi Jacobs collection, and a rare copy of the book Business Cards by Bengston and Ed Ruscha in the Wallace Berman papers.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Billy Al Bengston was born in Dodge City, Kansas on June 7, 1934. After moving back and forth from Kansas to California multiple times, he and his family settled in Los Angeles in 1948. While attending the Manual Arts High School, Bengston became interested in art, especially ceramics. After a brief stint at Los Angeles Junior College, Bengston worked as a beach attendant at Doheny State Beach. While working there he met fellow surfer and future ceramicist Kenneth Price, who became one of Bengston's closest friends. In 1953, he reenrolled in Los Angeles Junior College to study ceramics. For the next four years he attended both the California College of Arts and Crafts and the Los Angeles County Art Institute (now the Otis Art Institute of Parsons School of Design). At these institutions he studied with Richard Diebenkorn, Sabro Hasegawa, Nathan Oliveira, and Peter Voulkos.
Around 1957, Bengston shifted his emphasis from ceramics to painting, and became affiliated with the Ferus Gallery in Los Angeles, founded that same year by Edward Kienholz and Walter Hopps. Bengston's first solo exhibition was held at the Ferus Gallery in 1958, and a second followed in 1960. At this time Bengston began to work with Pop icons combined with Color Field abstractions. His early bold paintings often featured symmetrical strong color compositions with a central image of a valentine, star, cross, chevron, or iris. The irises he called "draculas," after Kenneth Price remarked that they resembled Dracula flying through a window. He first showed his chevron paintings in 1962 at the Martha Jackson Gallery in New York. In the early 1960s, Bengston extended his imagery to the California subculture and created paintings of leisure time activities, focusing on motorcycles, racing, and scuba diving - his own interests as well.
Throughout his career, Bengston experimented with technique and materials. He experimented with automobile lacquer and spray painting techniques associated with car customization. He also used non-traditional surfaces, such as masonite and aluminum. In 1965, Bengston began creating paintings on sheets of aluminum into which he hammered dents and sometimes bent and buckled; these subsequently came to be known as "dentos." Along with painting, Bengston has also created watercolors, ceramics, and furniture. He was also one of the artists selected by Carol and Roy Doumani to design their home.
Bengston first visited Hawaii in 1974, and after several subsequent trips, established a second studio there in 1979. The work Bengston created in the following years was characterized by the use of tropical colors and representational images of running figures, airplanes, and the moon. In 1988, the Contemporary Arts Museum in Houston organized a retrospective entitled "Billy Al Bengston: Paintings of Three Decades," which traveled to the Oakland Museum, the Los Angeles County Museum of Art, and the Contemporary Museum of Art, Honolulu. Bengston also completed several years as an art instructor and lecturer at the Chouinard Art Institute in Los Angeles and The University of California at Los Angeles. Bengston continues to create and exhibit new work.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Billy Al Bengston measure 10.2 linear feet and date from circa 1940s to 1989, with the bulk of the materials dating from 1960 to 1988. The collection documents the life and work of the southern California artist through biographical materials, correspondence, personal business records, gallery and museum files, teaching files, project and commission files, scattered artwork, printed materials, and photographs.
Found within the biographical materials series are three feet of calendars which extensively document Bengston's personal and professional activities for fourteen years, and include ephemera related to these activities. This series also includes health records, wills, and passports.
Correspondence is with galleries, museums, universities, businesses, friends, and colleagues, and primarily concerns exhibitions, sales, consignments, commissions, and Bengston's personal finances. Bengston's relationship with the James Corcoran Gallery, Janie C. Lee Gallery, John Berggruen Gallery, Martha Jackson Gallery, and Texas Gallery are well-documented here, as well as in the Museum and Gallery Files series. Also found is a limited amount of personal correspondence with collectors, researchers, and friends. A few letters from other artists, including Peter Plagens and a letter from Richard Diebenkorn are interfiled here.
Bengston's professional relationships with galleries, museums, and universities are well-documented in the gallery and museum files, including the galleries mentioned above, Ferus Gallery, and others. Lists of consignments and prices, invoices, records of sales, loan agreement forms, shipping receipts, exhibition checklists, and exhibition floor plans provide information about sales, exhibitions, and loans. A few files provide further information about Bengston teaching activities. His personal business records include art sales records, price lists, lists of purchases, records of investment, and personal finance records. Project files include correspondence, notes, and printed materials related to Bengston's commissions for artwork and personal projects, including a book he worked on with Ed Ruscha, Business Cards.
Writings by Bengston include responses to exhibitions of West Coast art and his thoughts on his career, art, the artistic community, motorcycles, as well as a recollection of John Altoon. Also found are questionnaires sent out by Bengston for an art survey, with responses from Peter Alexander, Carl Andre, John Chamberlain, Dan Flavin, Joe Goode, Robert Graham, Roy Lichtenstein, Robert Motherwell, Ed Ruscha, and others. Writings by others consist primarily of exhibition catalog essays, manuscripts of interviews with Bengston, and other writings about Bengston. Also found is an essay by Walter Hopps. Photographs of Bengston include a family picture from the 1940s, Bengston at work on projects in Los Angeles and Syracuse, New York, and Bengston at social events. Other photographs consist of pictures of friends and artists, Bengston's artwork, documentary evidence of damaged artwork, and of commission sites.
Printed materials from the 1960s - 1980s include clippings, full articles, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and posters. They document exhibitions, art in southern California, and society and art events. The collection houses limited amounts of artwork including sketches, cut-outs, doodles and drawings.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 10 series:
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1958-1987 (Boxes 1-4, 11; 3.7 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1966-1989 (Boxes 4-6; 1.75 linear feet)
Series 3: Gallery and Museum Files, 1961-1989 (Boxes 6-7; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 4: Teaching Records, 1968-1982 (Box 7; 7 folders)
Series 5: Personal Business Records, circa 1960-1987 (Boxes 7-8; 1.0 linear foot)
Series 6: Project Files, 1968-1987 (Boxes 8-9; 0.25 linear feet)
Series 7: Writings, 1967-circa 1988 (Box 9, OV 1; 0.25 linear feet)
Series 8: Artwork, 1960s-1987 (Box 9; 7 folders)
Series 9: Printed Materials, 1958-1988 (Boxes 9-10, OV 1-2; 1.25 linear feet)
Series 10: Photographs, circa 1940s-1987 (Box 10; 0.5 linear feet)
Alexander, Peter, 1939-; Altoon, John, 1925-; Andre, Carl, 1935-; Chamberlain, John, 1927-2011; Diebenkorn, Richard, 1922-1993; Ferus Gallery (Los Angeles, Calif.); Flavin, Dan, 1933-; Goode, Joe, 1937-; James Corcoran Gallery.; John Berggruen Gallery (San Francisco, Calif.); Lichtenstein, Roy, 1923-1997; Martha Jackson Gallery; Motherwell, Robert; Plagens, Peter; Ruscha, Edward; Art galleries, Commercial; Art--Economic aspects; Art--Study and teaching; Interviews; Painters--California; Photographs; Works of art
- Biographical Materials, 1958-1987; Series 1; 3.7 Linear feet Boxes 1-4, 11
  Scope and Contents note
  The bulk of this series consists of calendars dating from 1971 to 1984, in which Bengston recorded detailed daily activities, such as visiting galleries, social activities, travel, etc. Ephemera include receipts, exhibition announcements, and mailings that have been attached to calendar pages. A notebook contains information about Bengston's paints, works sold and exhibited at Ferus Gallery, lists of addresses, and scattered sketches. Health records detail the damage done to Bengston's back in a 1964 motorcycle accident. Also found here are passports from European and Central American trips, a Mexican travel visa, membership and business cards, certificates, telephone messages, and Bengston's will.
  Arrangement note
  Due to the presence of mold on calendar pages from 1971, these materials have been boxed separately.
  - Address List, circa 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baseball Card, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Jim Grant
  - Business Cards, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Calendars, January 1971-October 1977; (27 folders; see also Box 11) (Box 1, Folder 4-30)
  - Calendars, October 1977-March 1982; (23 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-23)
  - Calendars, March 1982-June 1984; (22 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-22)
  - Calendars, July 1984-December 1984; (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-7)
  - Certificate of Vaccination, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Certificates, 1978-1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chronology, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1968, circa 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Driving Citation, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Health Information, 1973, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Health Insurance Records, 1973-1984; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Membership Cards, circa 1969, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Notes, 1960s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Passports, 1958-1972 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Personal Telephone Directory, circa 1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Phone Bill, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Phone Messages, 1981-1984; (6 folders) (Box 4, Folder 22-27)
  - Phone Messages, Loose, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Recipe, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Shopping Cards, circa 1960s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Travel Visa, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Will of Billy Al Bengston, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Will of Raymond Bengston, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Calendars, 1971; (possible mold) (Box 11 (pam), Folder 1-4)
- Correspondence, 1966-1989; Series 2; 1.75 Linear feet Boxes 4-6
  The bulk of this series consists of Bengston's business correspondence, mostly to and from galleries and museums discussing exhibitions, sales, consignments, projects, and agreements. Bengston's relationship with the James Corcoran Gallery, Janie C. Lee Gallery, John Berggruen Gallery, Martha Jackson Gallery, and Texas Gallery are well-documented. Many business letters are written by Penny Little and Gretchen Corners in Bengston's name.
  The series also includes a limited amount of personal correspondence including letters with collectors, researchers, and friends. In addition, personal correspondence is often interfiled with the professional correspondence, particularly with gallery owners James Corcoran, Janie C. Lee, and Fredericka Hunter of the Texas Gallery. Also found are a few letters from other artists, including Peter Plagens and a letter from Richard Diebenkorn.
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by surname or business name. Correspondence related to Bengston's commissions can be found in Series 6, Project Files, and correspondence related to loans of artwork can be found in Series 5, Personal Business Records.
  - A-An, 1968-1987 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Ar-Av, 1970-1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Acquavella Contemporary Art, Inc., 1974-1986; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 36-38)
  - American Airlines, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Architectural Digest, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Archives of American Art, 1973-1981 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Art Frame, 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Art in America, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Automobile Club of Southern California, 1972, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - B-Bl, 1970-1987 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Bo-By, 1969-1987 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Paula Barton, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Andrew Bogle, 1981, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Brooke Alexander, Inc., 1969-1982; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 49-50)
  - C-Ce, 1967-1987 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Ch-Cl, 1969-1984 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Co-Cu, 1968-1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - California Arts Council, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - California State University, Long Beach, 1975-1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cantor/Lemberg Gallery, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Frances Causey, 1981-1984 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Condor Cycles, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Conejo Valley Museum, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Contemporary Arts Museum, 1979-1989; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1969, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - D, 1977-1984 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - David Finlay Gallery, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Diane Gilson Gallery, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Richard Diebenkorn, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Dobrick Gallery, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Dootson/Calderhead Gallery, 1975-1976, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Dorothy Rosenthal, 1975-1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Dorothy Drake Gallery, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - E, 1969-1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Edizioni O, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Greg Erickson, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Eve Mannes Gallery, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Everson Museum of Art, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - F, 1973-1986 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Feldman Gallery, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Felicity Samuel Gallery, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Fine Arts Services, 1980-1981, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - G, 1968-1986 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Galerie Neuendorf, 1970-1981, 1983-1984; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 30-31)
  - Helen Gilbert, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Gloria Luria Gallery, 1978-1982 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1975-1985 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - H-Hi, 1972-1986 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Ho-Hy, 1976-1984 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Honolulu Academy of Arts, 1974-1980 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - I, 1979-1984 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - J, 1969-1987 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - James Corcoran Gallery, 1971-1986; (6 folders) (Box 5, Folder 41-46)
  - Janie C. Lee Gallery, 1968-1973; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
  - Edwin Janss, 1976, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Jared Sabel Gallery, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - John Berggruen Gallery, 1981-1982; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 51-52)
  - K, 1970-1984 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Kadison, Pfaelzer, Woodward, Quinn, and Rossi, 1977, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Kuafman and Bernstein, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Laurence Klein, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Alkis Klonaridis, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - L-Ll, 1969-1987 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Lo-Lu, 1973-1985 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - La Brea Wilshire Travel Center, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - La Jolla Museum of Contemporary Art, 1971-1986 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Linda Farris Gallery, 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Locksley Shea Gallery, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1966-1969, 1977, 1980-1983, 1986; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 64-65)
  - Los Angeles International Film Exposition, 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - M-Mea, 1968-1987 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Med-Mi, 1973-1987 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Mo-My, 1969-1987 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Margo Leavin Gallery, 1971-1978, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Martha Jackson, 1962-1969, 1979; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 71-72)
  - Anthony Mathews, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Mizuno Gallery, 1970-1979 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Joan Mondale, 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Morgan, Olmstead, Kennedy, and Gardner, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Multiples Inc., 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art, 1982-1987 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Museum of Modern Art, 1966-1971, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - N, 1974-1987 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - National Endowment For the Arts, 1966-1970, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Rolf Nelson, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Newport Harbor Art Museum, 1975-1987 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Nicholas Wilder Gallery, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Nimslo Corporation, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - O, 1970-1988 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Oakland Museum, 1982-1983, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Office of the State Architect, 1974-1987 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Eliv Olesen, 1980, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Ollendorf Fine Arts, 1979, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - P-Ph, 1973-1986 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Pi-Pu, 1972-1986 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Pace Gallery, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Jose Paniagua, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Pasadena Art Museum, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Paul Stuart, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Michael Phillips, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Peter Plagens, 1971, 1974, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Pyramid Gallery, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Jack Quinn, 1976-1982 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - R-Re, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ri-Ry, 1969-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - William Radawec, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Reese Paley Gallery, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Mike Ross, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - S-San, 1969-1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Sar-Se, 1974-1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - St-Sw, 1971-1987 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Richard Salmon, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - San Diego State University, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, 1976-1984 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - San Francisco Tapestry Workshop, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - San Jose State University, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Seder/Creigh Gallery, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Sherry French Gallery, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Benjamin Smith, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Syracuse China Corporation, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - T-Ti, 1969-1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Tj-Tw, 1970-1984 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Tamarind Institute, 1968, 1978-1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Texas Gallery, 1970-1984; (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 22-25)
  - Thomas Babeor Gallery, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - James Tyler, 1975-1976, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - U-University of California, 1973-1986 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - University of Georgia-Ut, 1970-1986 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - University of California, Irvine, 1978-1985 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - University of California, Santa Barbara, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - University of Houston, 1978, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - University of Santa Clara, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Utah Museum of Fine Arts, 1967-1969 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - V, 1969-1987 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Vancouver Art Gallery, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Alberto Vasquez, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - W-Wa, 1972-1985 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - We-Wu, 1972-1984 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1969-1973, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Y, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 41)
- Gallery and Museum Files, 1961-1989; Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 6-7
  This series consists of a wide variety of materials documenting Bengston's business with galleries, museums, and universities, such as sales, exhibitions, and loans. Files may include consignment lists, price lists, invoices, pages from ledgers, shipping receipts, legal agreements, exhibition checklists, lists of catalog reproductions, floor plans, and mailing lists. Galleries represented in the files include the Ferus Gallery, James Corcoran Gallery, Janie C. Lee Gallery, John Berggruen Gallery, Martha Jackson Gallery, Texas Gallery, and Thomas Babeor Gallery. Extensive documentation exists for Bengston's 1968 retrospective at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art, his 1981 exhibition of watercolors at the Corcoran Gallery of Art, and his 1988 retrospective organized by the Contemporary Arts Museum.
  Note that the bulk of the correspondence with museums and galleries is found in Series 2 above. Folders relating to university galleries have been titled by the name of the university rather than the name of the gallery.
  - Acquavella Gallery, 1978-1986 (Box 6, Folder 42-45)
  - American Craft Museum, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Aspen Art Museum, circa 1986 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Auckland City Art Gallery, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - California State University, Fullerton, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Cantor/Lemberg Gallery, 1979-1983 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Conejo Valley Art Museum, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Contemporary Arts Center, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Contemporary Arts Museum, 1981, 1984, 1987-1989; (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 54-57)
  - Corcoran and Corcoran, Ltd., 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1980-1981; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 59-60)
  - David Anderson Gallery, 1981, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Diane Gilson Gallery, 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Dobrick Gallery, circa 1976 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Dootson/Calderhead Gallery, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Dorothy Rosenthal Gallery, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Douglas Drake Gallery, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Edizioni O, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Eve Mannes Galleries, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Everson Museum of Art, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Felicity Samuel Gallery, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Fendrick Gallery, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Ferus Gallery, 1961-1962, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Fuller Goldeen Gallery, 1978-1986 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Galerie Neuendorf, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Gloria Luria Gallery, circa 1982 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Hokim Kaufman Gallery, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Honolulu Academy of Arts, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Hunsaker/Schlesinger Gallery, 1981, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Indianapolis Museum of Art, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Jack Glenn Gallery, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - James Corcoran Gallery, 1976-1983; (12 folders) (Box 6, Folder 81-92)
  - James Corcoran Gallery, 1984-1986; (3 folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - Janie C. Lee, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Janus Gallery, 1980-1981, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Jared Sable Gallery, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - John Berggruen Gallery, 1973-1975, 1978-1985; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Joslyn Art Museum, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Koplin Gallery, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - La Jolla Museum of Contemporary Art, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - L.A. Louvre Gallery, 1982-1983 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Laguna Beach Museum of Art, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 13)